[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [4, 7, 0, 6], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [1, 3, 0, 2], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+40+T\u2081=4a\u2081", "-40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "-40+T\u2081=4a\u2081", "+40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "T\u2083: Tension in white string", "T\u2084: Tension in yellow string"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 downwards", "T\u2081 upwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+40+T\u2081=4a\u2081", "-40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "-40+T\u2081=4a\u2081", "+40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: 40", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+40+T\u2081=4a\u2082", "-40+T\u2081=4a\u2082", "+40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "-40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "+40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "T\u2083: Tension in white string", "T\u2084: Tension in yellow string"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards", "T\u2081 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+40+T\u2081=4a\u2082", "-40+T\u2081=4a\u2082", "+40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "-40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: 40", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2082+20=2a\u2083", "+T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "-T\u2082+20=2a\u2083", "-T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "+T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "T\u2083: Tension in white string", "T\u2084: Tension in yellow string"], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for blue block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on blue block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 upwards", "T\u2082 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2082+20=2a\u2083", "+T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "-T\u2082+20=2a\u2083", "-T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Downward Forces: 20", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of second pulley in the y-direction", "options": ["+2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "+2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "+2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "T\u2083: Tension in white string", "T\u2084: Tension in yellow string"], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for second pulley cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "answer": 3}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards ", "T\u2081 downwards "], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards ", "T\u2081 downwards "], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 upwards ", "T\u2082 downwards "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 3, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of second pulley in the y-direction", "options": ["+2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "+2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "+a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2083: acceleration of blue block in y-direction", "a\u2084: acceleration of second pulley in y-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the pink string?", "options": [7, 6, 4, 5], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 + l\u2084 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2084", "-a\u2084"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 + l\u2084 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2083 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2084", "-a\u2084"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 + l\u2084 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2084 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 + l\u2084 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 + l\u2084 = constant", "l\u2081'' = +a\u2081", "l\u2082'' = -a\u2084", "l\u2083'' = -a\u2084", "l\u2084'' = +a\u2082"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "type": "advance"}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2083+a\u2084=0", "+a\u2083-a\u2084=0", "-a\u2083+a\u2084=0", "-a\u2083-a\u2084=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "-a\u2083+a\u2084=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2083: acceleration of blue block in y-direction", "a\u2084: acceleration of second pulley in y-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2084", "-a\u2084"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2083+a\u2084=0", "+a\u2083-a\u2084=0", "-a\u2083+a\u2084=0", "-a\u2083-a\u2084=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant", "l\u2081'' = +a\u2084 -a\u2083"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "Red string: -a\u2083+a\u2084=0"], "type": "advance"}]}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= -6.0, a\u2082= -6.0, a\u2083= 6.0, a\u2084= 6.0, T\u2081= 16.0, T\u2082= 32.0, T\u2083= 32.0, T\u2084= 32.0", "a\u2081= -6.0, a\u2082= -6.0, a\u2083= -32.0, a\u2084= -32.0, T\u2081= 6.0, T\u2082= -16.0, T\u2083= 6.0, T\u2084= -32.0", "a\u2081= -6.0, a\u2082= -32.0, a\u2083= -6.0, a\u2084= -16.0, T\u2081= -32.0, T\u2082= 6.0, T\u2083= -32.0, T\u2084= 6.0", "a\u2081= -16.0, a\u2082= 6.0, a\u2083= -32.0, a\u2084= -6.0, T\u2081= -32.0, T\u2082= 6.0, T\u2083= -32.0, T\u2084= -6.0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "Red string: -a\u2083+a\u2084=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2081", "Yellow block: +40-T\u2081=4a\u2082", "Blue block: +T\u2082-20=2a\u2083", "Second pulley: +2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: +a\u2081+a\u2082-2a\u2084=0", "Red string: -a\u2083+a\u2084=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= -6.0, a\u2082= -6.0, a\u2083= 6.0, a\u2084= 6.0, T\u2081= 16.0, T\u2082= 32.0, T\u2083= 32.0, T\u2084= 32.0"]}]}]